# KHYATI THAKUR

SR. SOFTWARE ENGINEER

#### **PERSONAL PROFILE**

Experienced software engineer with a demonstrated history of creating customer-facing and in-house technical products. Skilled in scaling cloud infrastructure, Agile methodologies, and User Interface Design. Strong engineering professional with a demonstrated experience in both frontend and backend tech stacks. Proven leadership characteristics and have successfully managed high performing software engineering teams in an Agile environment.

## **EDUCATION**

### University of Southern California, US

Masters in Computer Science, May 2015

#### University of Mumbai, India

Bachelor in Computer Science, May 2011

## **CONTACT INFORMATION**



+919607612762



khyatithakur6@gmail.com



https://github.com/khyatith



Pune, MH, India

#### **EMPLOYMENT**

# Realtor.com, Santa Clara, CA Jun 2018 - Apr 2022

#### Sr. Software Engineer

- Used Javascript frameworks and libraries like Next.js, React.js, and Node.js to build the consumer-facing feature of scheduling a listing tour on realtor.com.
- Led the team to develop a chatbot using Twilio services and React.js front-end to help consumers answer questions about listing details.
- Created a config-driven UI micro-service in React.js to enable engineers to make changes to and add new templates of the lead forms on the website.
- Worked closely with data analytics to improve the tracking system capability to better collect and interpret data and reports for important company metrics.
- Created GraphQL schemas and reducers to request and display the consumer, agent and listing data on the front-end.
- Worked closely with Product Managers to implement and analyze features and KPIs.
- **Mentored junior engineers** in the team to help them better align themselves with their quarterly goals.

# GumGum Inc, Los Angeles, CA Jan 2015 - Jun 2018

## Web Engineer

- Used PHP and JQuery to develop the features on the company dashboard that enabled Sales and Marketing teams to make decisions based on data.
- Worked closely with designers to create the visualizations on the dashboard using D3.js that makes it easier for the Csuite to view the data in a comprehensive way.
- Solely responsible for developing an online ad-demo tool for the sales team using HTML/CSS, React.js, and Node.js. to enable the sales team to create demos for GumGum ads.
- Created an Ad builder tool on React.js, Node.js, AWS EC2 and AWS S3 that enabled Ad designers to create different Ads for GumGum.
- **Mentored junior engineers** on the tech-stack and their engineering goals.
- Worked with Product Manager to create OKRs for the engineering team and KPIs for our team to help our team be aligned with the company metrics and goals.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Programming Languages: Javascript, React.js, Node.js, Next.js, GraphQL, HTML, CSS, PHP, Flutter
- Databases: MYSQL, SQLite, MongoDB, documentDB, DynamoDB
- Cloud: Heroku, Firebase, AWS (Lambda, S3, Cloudformation, EC2, SQS, SNS, RDS, Redis, ECS)
- Applications: Visio, Adobe Photoshop, Axure RP

#### LEADERSHIP SKILLS

PROBLEM SOLVER

STRONG COMMUNICATION SKILLS

DEMONSTRATED LEADERSHIP

**ORGANIZED & SELF-SUFFICIENT** 

ATTENTION TO DETAIL

# Infosys Ltd, Pune, IN Aug 2011 - Oct 2013

# UI/UX Designer

- Carried out HTML/CSS front-end development, usability testing, troubleshooting, wireframe creation, interface design for eCommerce/Billing applications.
- Worked as an **Android application developer** to develop Billing applications for Telecom providers.
- Worked as a UX/UI researcher to create design solutions for internal clients and internal Infosys applications like referral portal.
- Mentored a team of designers and conducted design workshops for designers to help them better understand the competitive analysis paradigm of designing.